Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ amandawrightphd (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Analytics
Python (Programming Language)
Critical Thinking

Certifications

Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization

SQL Essential Training

The Data Science of Experimental Design

6.041x: Introduction to Probability: Part 1 - The Fundamentals

6.00.1x Introduction to Computer Science and Programming using Python

Honors-Awards

Open Source Excellence award

Amanda Wright

Data Analytics | Python | Machine Learning
Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

Summary

I am a skilled scientist versed in Python, statistical analysis, and machine learning who understands the power of data to solve problems, discover information, and uncover hidden patterns. I am keen to gain experience helping a business use data to solve problems and make decisions.

I have a Ph.D. in biology and previously worked as an academic scientist. I was drawn to biological research as a career because I have a passion for asking questions, conducting experiments, and synthesizing data. Working as a biologist honed my skills in designing and conducting experiments, analyzing data, and interpreting and communicating the results to stakeholders.

Intrigued by the possibilities of 'big data', I worked independently and with a data science boot camp to acquire the technical tools used by data analysts and data scientists. I am now proficient in writing code in Python, building machine learning pipelines, writing queries in SQL, and creating visualizations with Tableau. I have always been an enthusiastic learner and have truly enjoyed immersing myself in the data science field and creating various personal projects to highlight my new skill set.

I am currently working in my first data analytics position. I bring solid technical skills, well-developed soft skills, an "always learning" attitude, and an eagerness to make an impact in my new industry and career.

I am happy to connect with fellow data enthusiasts so please reach out!

Experience

WW

Data Analyst November 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

University of North Texas Assistant Professor of Biology 2009 - 2018 (9 years)

- Conceived and conducted original research working to understand plant cell division
- Awarded over \$1.3 million in research grants including an NSF CAREER grant
- Trained and mentored undergraduate students, graduate students, and postdoctoral researchers
- Communicated ideas to undergraduate and graduate students via teaching classes and mentoring and to my peers via writing grants and papers and giving presentations

University of California at San Diego Postdoctoral Research Fellow 2005 - 2009 (4 years) Greater San Diego Area

I had an IRACDA fellowship that supported my original research on asymmetric plant cell division in Dr. Laurie Smith's laboratory and provided opportunities for me to teach introductory biology lectures at SDSU.

Harvard University Postdoctoral Scientist 2003 - 2005 (2 years)

Conducted original research on RNA interference in nematodes in Dr. Craig Hunter's laboratory.

Education

K2 Data Science
Machine Learning · (2019 - 2021)

Harvard University PhD, Biology

Texas Tech University
BS, Cell and Molecular Biology